<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Introduction</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Overview of the CAS module">

            <subsection name="Introduction">
            <p>
                <img src="images/cas.jpg" />This module provides to the users an authentication with the CAS SSSO.
            </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Prerequisites">
            <p>
                In order to follow this tutorial, a knowledge of SSO and in particular of the CAS solution is needed.
            </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>

        <section name="Definition of SSO">

            <p>The SSO (Single Sign On) is a method allowing a user to proceed with only one authentication to access several protected applications </p>

        </section>

        <section name="Overview of authentication with CAS">
            <subsection name="Introduction">

            <p>CAS means "Central Authentication Service". This SSO System is developed by the Yale University.  
            </p>

            <p>CAS is based on exchange of tickets between the client browser, the authentication server and the protected application.
            </p>

            <p>The following schema illustrates how the CAS server manages the SSO authentication.
                <center><img src="images/cas.png" /></center>
                <pre>
                1 : The client requests the protected application
                2 : The client is redirected by the application towards the CAS server
                3 : After the client authentication on CAS, it delivers a ticket and redirects the client towards the application
                4 : The application reads the ticket and verifies it on CAS. 
                </pre>
            </p>

            </subsection>

        </section>

        <section name="Deployment of a Lutece application protected by CAS module">

The procedure to deploy an application protected by CAS is the following one :
<ul>
<li>deployment of the plugin mylutece and the module CAS in the application</li> 
<li>setting of the module CAS : the mylutece-cas.role.name role defines in the properties file of the plugin makes it possible to restrict the access to the pages having this role to the users authenticated with CAS. </li>
<li>setting of the server CAS (cf documentation on CAS))</li>        
</ul>
</section>



    </body>
</document>